github.com/binSmile | linkedin.com/in/vitaliy-shkoldin | ShkoldinVA@gmail.com | +381 611 078 227

Summary

As a proficient scientist, I possess a strong analytical mindset and additionally broad experience in high-tech. I readily absorb new knowledge and can solve complex problems through innovative solutions. Moreover, I place high value on user experience.

Work Experience

<u>LoyaltyPlant</u> – is an all-in-one digital platform for global quick service restaurants

Product Analyst

4 months | June 2024 - Sep 2024

- B2B data reports, data verification

Deeplay.io – Al-driven animators for card games

ETL Data Engineer

1 year | July 2023 - June 2024

- Apache Airflow (ETL): raw python and pandas data processing: APIs, MySQL, Google Sheets, ClickHouse
- Maintain documentation, mentorships

ITMO University & Alferov University

Leading universities in the field of nanophotonics and semiconductors.

Research engineer | Data acquisition & Data Analyst

5.5 years | May 2017 - Dec 2022

- Collection, refinement, and analysis of experimental data, hypnotize verification
- Assembling optical setups and direct involvement in execution of optical experiments
- Performing analysis and automation of experimental data processing using Python (Pandas) and data visualization employing Matplotlib and Seaborn for presentations in publications and conferences
- Enhancing equipment capabilities through the use of microcontrollers (C++, LabView)
- Conducting market and technological research
- Secured 5 research grants (application, managing, teamwork, reporting)

NT-SPb – a scientific equipment manufacturer, spin-off of the global giant NT-MDT.

Engineer

4 years | May 2018 – Sep 2022

- Engaging in R&D and customizing equipment to meet client specifications
- Performing on-site and remote equipment installations, support
- Conducting software and hardware testing

Skills set

Python (Pandas, NumPy, ...), Proficient MS Excel, SQL, BASH, LabView, Orange Data Mining, Airflow, ETL, Matplotlib, Data Lens, Looker Studio, Redash, GIT, Jira, YouTrack, Linux, Docker English, Russian (Native)

Education

2022 <u>Ph.D. in Physics</u> 2011 - 2017 M.Sc. & B.Sc. Cond-matter physics
Electronics and nanoelectronics

St. Petersburg ITMO University

St. Petersburg Polytechnic University